<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<resume>

	<contact>
		<name>Kevin J. McIntyre</name>
		<address1>14371 Riveria Dr.</address1>
		<address2>Huntington Beach, CA 92647</address2>
		<phone>(718) 249-5058</phone>
		<email>kevin70@yahoo.com</email>
	</contact>

	<skill title="Core Skills">
		<list>
			Architecture,
			Java,
			MVC,
			Scripting,
			SQL,
			UI,
			Web Services
		</list>
	</skill>

	<skill title="J2EE">
		<list>
			EJB, JMS, JTA, Hibernate, Servlets, SOAP, Spring, Python
		</list>
	</skill>

	<skill title="Servers">
		<list>
			Apache, Jboss, Shibboleth
		</list>
	</skill>

	<skill title="Tools">
		<list>
			Eclipse, Junit, Linux, Maven, Revision Control
		</list>
	</skill>

	<skill title="Scripting">
		<list>
			Bash, JSP, Perl, PHP, Python, Ruby
		</list>
	</skill>

	<skill title="SQL">
		<list>
			MSSQL, MySQL, Postgres, Oracle
		</list>
	</skill>

	<skill title="UI">
		<list>
			AJAX, FOP, HTML, POI, Javascript, JQuery, JSON
		</list>
	</skill>

	<header>
		<title>Objective</title>
		<description>
			Seeking a position in software architecture, acting as lead developer,
			business liaison, and mentor to other developers.
		</description>
	</header>

	<header>
		<title>Overview</title>
		<description>
			From 1996 through 2000 my experience was in web design/UI, coding all
			aspects of the web with ASP, Perl, Cold Fusion, MSSQL.
			Since 1999, I've concentrated on Java software development utilizing open
			source software.
		</description>
		<description>
			I have experience with many OSS technologies since their inception, as
			these technologies have proliferated, I've engineered solutions based
			on the Agile and DRY development philosophies.
		</description>
		<description>
			Though I consider myself capable UI developer, my strengths are best
			utilized in the middle-tier conceptualizing business logic as sound,
			secure software.
		</description>
		<description>
			My coding philosophy is to trivialize software by
		</description>
	</header>

	<job>
		<title>Java Architect</title>
		<company>Freelancers Union</company>
		<stay>4/2008 &#8211; 2/2011</stay>

		<descriptions>
			<stuff>Lead developer on a </stuff>
			<linkto url="www.freelancersinsuranceco.com/">medical portal</linkto>
			<stuff> for the Freelancers Union.

				Key member during project planning phase, advising on software
				infrastructure, researching solutions, and authoring project
				documentation.

				Implemented project using Eclipse, SVN, Maven, Xdoclet, MantisBT targeting
				Linux/CentOS running Apache, Jboss 4.2.3, and Oracle 11g.

				Developed standards-based enterprise application with hibernate model, a
				business-tier, and servlet/jsp controllers/views.

				Application featured services that serialized third-party
			</stuff>
			<linkto url="en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Electronic_Data_Interchange">EDI</linkto>
			<stuff> file into a data warehouse.

				Incoming data was subsequently audited and transformed to a portal-tier.

				Web application featured
			</stuff>
			<linkto url="en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Single_sign-on">SSO</linkto>
			<stuff> modules to view patient claims information on third-party
				websites written in OpenSAML and SAML 2.0.

				Developed administrative web application for call center representatives to
				view enrollment changes, and manage portal users.

				Responsibilities included porting application and data from Oracle to Postgres, and
				porting website from proprietary CMS to Ruby
			</stuff>
			<linkto url="webgen.rubyforge.org">Webgen</linkto>
			<stuff>.

				Also, performed key roles through two billing/enrollment vendor
				transitions, contributing as quality assurance tester, business
				liaison, and lead developer spanning the lifecycle of the projects.

				Additional development duties included upgrades to multiple
			</stuff>
			<linkto url="be.freelancersunion.org/yp/">Frelancers</linkto>
			<stuff>
			</stuff>
			<linkto url="be.freelancersunion.org/gigs/">Union</linkto>
			<stuff> web applications, development of member demographic sync with
				third party administrator, and writing </stuff>
			<linkto
				url="fu-res.org/pdfs/insurance/health/2011/summary-of-benefits-ppo-1.pdf">summary of benefits</linkto>
			<stuff>/</stuff>
			<linkto
				url="fu-res.org/pdfs/insurance/health/2011/ppo1-benefits-booklet.pdf">benefit booklet</linkto>
			<stuff> PDF generator using </stuff>
			<linkto url="xmlgraphics.apache.org/fop/">FOP 0.95</linkto>
			<stuff>.

				Also contributed on projects
			</stuff>
			<linkto url="apps.facebook.com/jobtrackr">Jobtrackr</linkto>
			<stuff>, Freelancers Union's Facebook application, </stuff>
			<linkto url="www.freelancersunion.org/about/buzzmap/index.html">Buzz Map</linkto>
			<stuff>, and </stuff>
			<linkto url="www.freelancersunion.org/insurance/explore">explore insurance</linkto>
			<stuff>.</stuff>
		</descriptions>
	</job>

	<job>
		<title>Senior Consultant</title>
		<company>Crunch Fitness</company>
		<stay>10/2006 &#8211; 3/2008</stay>
		<descriptions>
			<stuff>
				Engineered enterprise Swing application for an industry leading health club
				chain.

				Application featured JNLP WebStart client brokering calls via EJB SessionBeans
				to a server, running Jboss 4.0.5 and MSSQL 2005.

				Took ownership of source code (2500 source files/1800 sql scripts) and
				release cycle from 3rd-party vendor, responsible for all facets of
				development.

				Established a test environment, installed
			</stuff>
			<linkto url="trac.edgewall.org/">tracking software</linkto>
			<stuff> to manage bugs and feature requests.

				Participated in end-user focus groups, worked closely with management to
				identify priorities, and coordinated development schedule.

				Rewrote build scripts, leveraging Jboss Remoting to reduce client size and
				memory footprint.

				Refactored code to use Log4j and configured Jboss log4j.xml to isolate logging
				of specific functions, enhancing error monitoring.

				Stabilized server component by coding to J2EE standards, eliminating spec
				violations such as thread spawning, and non-final public static
				variables.

				Enhanced client, improving security using IP and MAC addressing, resolving
				cross-country latency issues while implementing or fixing
				bugs/features.

				Acted as DBA: modified schema to implement new features, wrote stored
				procedures using cursors and common table expressions, scheduled
				nightly jobs, lead initiative to boost database performance, and
				eliminated database locking.

				Additional duties included Cold Fusion development on the
			</stuff>
			<linkto url="www.onlineccs.com">corporate sales website</linkto>
			<stuff>, and ASP.net development on the </stuff>
			<linkto url="www.crunch.com">public facing website</linkto>
			<stuff>.
			</stuff>
		</descriptions>
	</job>

	<job>
		<title>Software Developer</title>
		<company>Iamplify.com</company>
		<stay>7/2005 &#8211; 8/2006</stay>
		<descriptions>
			<stuff>
				Lead software development at
			</stuff>
			<linkto url="www.iamplify.com">Iamplify.com</linkto>
			<stuff>.

				Server administrator for linux servers running Apache2 (mod_php &amp; </stuff>
			<linkto url="www.oscommerce.com">OSCommerce</linkto>
			<stuff>), Jboss, Ruby, and MySQL.

				Project lead for
			</stuff>
			<linkto url="www.iamplify.com/sell">embedded flash player</linkto>
			<stuff> initiative, and lead developer of associated reporting tool,
				providing key metrics such as registrations, purchases, and
				downloads.

				Lead development on co-branded storefronts (</stuff>
			<linkto url="harpercollins.iamplify.com">HarperCollins</linkto>
			<stuff>) written using Eclipse, Maven, and Xdoclet.

				Coded servlets, listeners, and taglibs, utilizing a custom templating
				engine.

				Developed deployment tool enabling designers and content managers to easily
				tweak, test and deploy each storefront.

				Additional duties included PHP scripting on fulfillment system, and
				development of
			</stuff>
			<linkto url="mediafactory.iamplify.com">media tools website</linkto>
			.
			<stuff>
			</stuff>
		</descriptions>
	</job>

	<job>
		<title>Software Consultant</title>
		<company>Blueprint</company>
		<stay>1/2004 &#8211; 2/2005</stay>
		<descriptions>
			<stuff>Consultant to </stuff>
			<linkto url="blueprint.com">Blueprint</linkto>
			<stuff>, a pharmaceutical branding company.

				Lead developer of application connecting doctors and patients.

				Established a data center, and lead development through multiple
				life-cycles, working with graphic designers and a junior developer.

				Coded application using Eclipse, Xdoclet, and Maven that featured a
				local EJB persistence model, EJB Session Beans, JMS communications
				incorporating 5 websites, and JAAS method level role association.

				Written with Xdoclet to be application server and database agnostic,
				and ran seamlessly on Jboss/MySQL and WebLogic/Oracle
				infrastructure.

				Additional duties included work on client websites such as

			</stuff>
			<linkto url="www.rockport.com">Rockport</linkto>
			<stuff>, and </stuff>
			<linkto url="www.dfking.com">DFKing</linkto>
			<stuff>.
			</stuff>
		</descriptions>
	</job>

	<job>
		<title>Consultant</title>
		<company>NYC Department of Probation</company>
		<stay>12/2002 &#8211; 1/2004</stay>
		<descriptions>
			<stuff>
				Consultant to NYC Department of Probation, lead developer on automated
				probationer check-in system, managing 4 junior developers.

				Application utilized touch-screen monitor, and active-x controllers
				for web-cameras, palm-scanners, and printing.

				Developed using with Eclipse, Ant, and Xdoclet using remote EJB CMP Beans
				connecting to Informix database,
				JMS topics for probationer alerts, unit testing with JUnit, and MVC
				architecture with Struts form handling.

				Additional duties included Cold Fusion work on intranet website.
			</stuff>
		</descriptions>
	</job>

	<job>
		<title>Consultant</title>
		<company>MTVi.com</company>
		<stay>9/2000 &#8211; 3/2001</stay>
		<descriptions>
			<stuff>
				Consultant to MTVi.com, establishing Q &amp; A methodologies, and lead testing
				on ecommerce initiative.

				Installed
			</stuff>
			<linkto url="www.bugzilla.org">bug tracking software</linkto>
			<stuff> on Redhat 7.0, configuring Perl scripts to eliminate unused
				features.

				Wrote test cases, performed load testing, and mentored developers in best
				practices.

				Initiated weekly meetings to review bugs, and coordinate development and
				release schedules.

				Authored perl 404 finder to test targeted website for missing images.
			</stuff>
		</descriptions>
	</job>


	<job>
		<title>Lead Developer</title>
		<company>Volatile Media</company>
		<stay>3/1999 &#8211; 8/2000</stay>
		<descriptions>
			<stuff>
				Lead developer for Volatile Media, owner of multimedia start-up
				EZCD.com.

				Responsible for production infrastructure of a custom CD burning service,
				featuring samples of music as well as game demos for creating a
				custom mixed media CD.

				Developed websites using MSSQL, Cold Fusion, and java services supporting
				back-end manufacturing.

				Developed mailing-list, calendar, and content management tools allowing
				artists to promote their music.

				Responsible for interviewing/hiring junior developers and managed aspects of a
				small office including networking, Exchange server, and ISP
				relationships.
			</stuff>
		</descriptions>
	</job>


	<job>
		<title>Developer</title>
		<company>Lexitrans</company>
		<stay>10/1996 &#8211; 5/1999</stay>
		<descriptions>
			<stuff>
				Developer for Lexitrans, an online credit card transaction company.

				Coded and maintained state of the art membership billing system
				supporting 300,000 active members with real-time,
				and batch transactions using Cold Fusion, MSSQL, and X.25
				communications for credit card authorization/transaction.

				Lead developer of call center software employing 150 people authoring
				html forms, db schema, stored procedures, and nightly scheduled
				tasks.

				Developed content naming convention and lead development of site scheduler
				for managing updates, mentoring designers in content creation.

				Participated in data center re-location and conversion from Cold
				Fusion/MSSQL to ATG Dynamo/Oracle.
			</stuff>
		</descriptions>
	</job>
</resume>